Don Yoder collection of tape and disc recordings
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46846; 1 sound tape reel (01:36:28): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR012)
    Digitization notes: The audio is distorted, but can still be understood. The interview and the singing were probably not recorded on the same occasion, so one or both may have been dubbed to this tape.
    At 00:00:28 the interview begins: Mr. David K [sic], a member of the Amish Mennonite faith, speaks about his view of the future for the Amish Mennonite sect, missionary work, and other subjects. The interview ends at 00:39:36. A group performs four Amish Mennonite church spirituals. Audible information ends at 01:25:19.
  - Sound recording, circa 1989, RAA 46847; 1 sound tape reel (00:16:04): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR013)
    Digitization notes: The original tape appears to have been recorded on the first track only. However, an echo/print-through is present on the second track. The engineer made a stereo transfer to keep the extra audio in the same file as the main audio, as it appears on the master tape. The extra track sounds like an error and simply a copy of the main audio, so it does not fit the common definition of "stereo."
    Interview with Karlheinz Roenigk [?], in German (probably Pennsylvania German) and in English. Audio ends at 00:15:06.
  - Sound recording, July 1951, RAA 46848; 1 sound tape reel (00:29:38): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR014)
    2nd Annual Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival, Kutztown Fair Grounds; Kutztown, Pennsylvania. Broadcast by WEEU radio Special Affairs Department. AFC 2003/051: SR018 may be a copy of this recording.
    Don Yoder introduces Mrs. Sophie Bailer, a powwow. The announcer (named Nan) for WEEU speaks over Bailer's last song. George Carroll (WEEU) introduces segment on three main Pennsylvania Dutch myths. Dr. Alfred L. Shoemaker (director of the folk festival) speaks. George Carroll makes closing announcement over the voice of the speaker.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46849; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:31:01, Side B: 00:22:04): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR015)
    Content includes a group performing an unidentified song, in Pennsylvania German.
    Performers include Earl Keller, The Little Jiggers (who dance to "Irish Washerwoman"), and a performance by The Western Berks Group (square dancers), with Cheshnell Floppy [?], leader
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46850; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:10:47, Side B: 00:16:19): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 3/4 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR016)
    North Bend Choir members introduce themselves: Betty Rohrman, Loretta Landis, Merle Bishop, Grace Shye, Harold Shiser, Ray Landis, and Eugene Barette. Don Yoder [?] introduces the song the group will perform: "Leibe Heinrich" (Dear Henry.
    Don Yoder [?] introduces the next song. Peter Kirschner [?] performs a song about conversion, then the song "Come to Your Jesus." Don Yoder [?] introduces Ollie Streiser, who performs the song "Schwarz, Schwarz, Schwarz, Alle Meine G____". Audio is cut off both at the beginning and at the end of the recording.
  - Sound recording, July 3, 1958, RAA 46851; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:24:22, Side B: 00:24:34): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 3/4 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR017)
    Probably recorded at a Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival.
    Don Yoder moderates a program on secular music brought to the US by German and Swiss immigrants. Performers include The Buchmans (male singing group), Maggie Oberholzer, Victor Diefenbach, and Clayton Willyer. The next part of the program includes two revival songs performed by Peter Kirschner. The program closes with a performance by Ollie Strauser. Continues on SR017, Side B.
    Continues from SR017, Side A. Other performers demonstration groups: include Earl Keller, The Little Jiggers, who dance to "Irish Washerwoman," The Western Berks Group (square dancers), with Cheshnell Floppy [?], Norman Huntsigger (?) and the Keystone Jiggers (jig dancers), and Shtibley [?] Rex Dancers. There is a gap in the recording occurs between 00:10:33-00:10:52. The end of the recording is distorted, and cuts off suddenly. This seems to be a dub copy of the original tape. See SR015, Side B.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46852; 1 sound tape reel (00:29:53): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR018)
    Recorded at the Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival, Kutztown, Pennsylvania. Don Yoder leads a discussion on powwowing and myths; probably a folk festival held at Kutztown Fair Grounds. Principals are Don Yoder and Sophie Bailer. Also present: George Carroll and Alfred L. Shoemaker. The content may match part or all of AFC 2003/051: SR014.
  - Sound recording, July 1951, RAA 46853; 1 sound tape reel (00:30:09): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR019)
    2nd Annual Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Festival, Kutztown Fair Grounds, Kutztown, Pennsylvania. Telecast by WEEU radio Special Affairs Department.
    00:00:02 program of Pennsylvania German spirituals; George Carroll (announcer)
    00:00:30 Don Yoder gives the history of churches in Pennsylvania Dutch country, and bush meetings
    00:02:15 Rev. Harry Menser (Valley View, Pennsylvania) speaks in Pennsylvania German and English
    00:05:52 Lykens Valley group sings "In the Wilderness" (in Pennsylvania German)
    00:07:10 group sings "...Yerusalem" (in Pennsylvania German)
    00:08:12 group sings a song in Pennsylvania German
    00:09:15 group sings "Ich Wil Schape" in Pennsylvania German
    00:10:24 group sings a song in Pennsylvania German
    00:11:23 group sings "Wie Lieblich __ Yesus" in Pennsylvania German
    00:13:25 group sings a song in Pennsylvania German
    00:14:46 group sings a song in Pennsylvania German
    00:16:14 group sings "__ dem Himmel" in Pennsylvania German
    00:17:04 group sings "O Himmel O Himmel Wie Siese Bi Schtu"
    00:18:17 group sings "Singet Halleluyah" (?) in Pennsylvania German
    00:19:22 Don Yoder introduces Peter Kirschner
    00:19:52 Peter Kirschner performs "Our Family Worship Him"
    00:20:47 Don Yoder introduces next song
    00:21:01 Peter Kirschner sings "O Hah Shengun Stig Naude" (O Lord Send Us Thy Blessing) (to the tune of "Oh Dear, What Can the Matter Be")
    00:22:13 Don Yoder describes the preceding song; asks Peter Kirschner what he will sing next
    00:22:41 Peter Kirschner sings "Yesus Mit __" (Jesus Has Been With Us, and He Still is With Us, and He Says He Will Go With Us To the End) in Pennsylvania German
    00:23:47 Don Yoder describes the preceding song and introduces next song
    00:24:10 Peter Kirschner sings "Droben in Dem Schene Himmel" in Pennsylvania German
    00:25:14 Don Yoder introduces the Bush Meeting Singers
    00:25:44 Bush Meeting Singers (from Lykens Valley, Pennsylvania) perform "Roll, Jordan, Roll" (in English)
    00:26:28 Bush Meeting Singers perform "On the Resurrection Morning We Shall Rise" (in English)
    00:27:32 Bush Meeting Singers perform "We Spare A Prayer..." (in English)
    00:28:09 Bush Meeting Singers perform "Down in the Depths of the Deepest Sea" (in English)
    00:28:56 Don Yoder makes closing comments
    00:29:19 George Carroll makes the closing announcement for WEEU Radio
  - Sound recording, 1966, RAA 46854; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 01:03:57, Side B: 01:03:56): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR020)
    Russian-German church (or prayer) service (Brüderschaft meeting), Zion Church, Lincoln, Nebraska. Recorded by Roger Welsch. Buzzing distortion during approximately the first 12 minutes of the program. Three seconds of dropout from 00:32:16 to 00:32:19. Audio cut off abruptly at the end of the program.
    00:00:08 starts with piano introduction, which then accompanies group of people (congregation?) during singing
    00:03:55 unidentified men, speaking
    00:04:02 starts with piano introduction, which then accompanies group of people (congregation?) during singing
    00:07:58 unidentified men, speaking
    00:08:35 unidentified man speaks briefly, then sings a cappella, with piano joining shortly after he begins
    00:11:34 sounds of microphone position adjustment, and an unidentified man speaks in English and Pennsylvania German
    00:11:52 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German; names Bruder [Brother] [?], Bruder Alex Miller (Flint, Michigan); Bruder Wilhelm [others named?]
    00:12:46 starts with piano introduction, which then accompanies group of people (congregation?) during singing
    00:14:54 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:15:47 unidentified man leads group in singing a song in Pennsylvania German (a cappella)
    00:16:56 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:20:01 unidentified man leads a song in Pennsylvania German, and the group joins shortly afterwards
    00:20:34 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:22:59 unidentified man leads a song in Pennsylvania German, and the group joins shortly afterwards
    00:23:30 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German; another unidentified man introduces and leads the next song
    00:33:28 group performs a song (in Pennsylvania German)
    00:34:03 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:42:44 unidentified man introduces the next song, speaking in Pennsylvania German
    00:43:00 group performs a song (in Pennsylvania German), led by the same man as above
    00:43:56 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:45:50 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German
    00:46:23 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:55:19 unidentified man speaks in English; he refers to Brother Snyder's request that he should speak in English, but instead asks group to sing the next song in Pennsylvania German
    00:55:31 starts with piano introduction, which then accompaniment for the group during singing
    00:56:52 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German and English
    Church (or prayer) service. See notes for SR020, Side A. Brief dropout in the audio at 00:02:06. Some distortion during the third selection. Dropout from 00:03:35-00:03:41, followed by brief section recorded too fast. No audio from 00:59:28 - 00:59:33. Audio cut off abruptly at the end of the program.
    00:00:01 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German and English
    00:02:14 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German [the song is introduced with and accompanied by piano playing]
    00:05:16 several individuals speak, with each person saying private prayers aloud (?) in Pennsylvania German; during this time a voice in the background can be heard speaking, and growing louder, until it becomes more obvious that his is the leading voice
    00:07:14 unidentified man's voice finally becomes dominant (and he speaks in Pennsylvania German)
    00:08:18 another unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:09:52 group sings a song in Pennsylvania German, with piano accompaniment
    00:12:49 unidentified man speaks (in Pennsylvania German), followed by several individuals, with each person saying private prayers aloud (?) in Pennsylvania German
    00:15:05 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:15:12 unidentified man leads song in Pennsylvania German; soon after he is joined by group and piano accompaniment
    00:18:14 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:18:32 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German (with brief piano introduction, and continued accompaniment)
    00:19:45 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:23:46 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German (with brief piano introduction, and continued accompaniment)
    00:25:17 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:25:24 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German (with piano accompaniment)
    00:26:22 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:31:49 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German (with brief piano introduction, and continued accompaniment)
    00:33:28 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:37:45 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German (with brief piano introduction, and continued accompaniment)
    00:39:30 unidentified man speaks (in Pennsylvania German); he begins speaking before the singing ends
    00:43:51 pianist begins playing, and singers hesitantly begin to join in
    00:44:15 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:44:31 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German, a cappella (part of the group carrying the tune and words more strongly overwhelm the other part of group, which joins them; the piano may also perhaps be heard
    00:47:06 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:48:01 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German, accompanied by piano
    00:50:55 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:58:45 group performs a song in Pennsylvania German (may be accompanied by piano)
    00:59:21 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:59:34 various people talking, following by music
    01:02:09 instrumental segment
  - Sound recording, December 6, 1977, RAA 46855; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 01:29:36, Side B: 00:02:15): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR021)
    Yoder speaks at a festival held in honor of Thomas Nast. Digitization note for SR021: the tape broke during digitization. Points were reattached with fresh splice tape and the transfer was completed. While it seems that audio was recorded only on one track, there is a significant amount of cross-talk/print-through on the other track.
    Brief audio dropout from 00:16:04-00:16:05.
    00:00:08 audio fades in (includes Christmas music; orchestral only)
    00:06:26 music ends; audience applauds
    00:06:46 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:19:05 orchestral music
    00:24:20 Don Yoder speaks in Pennsylvania German and briefly in English; he mentions Thomas Nast (German illustrator, in part responsible for the current, popular image of Santa Claus)
    00:56:49 Don Yoder speaks in Pennsylvania German
    00:57:31 whistling sound
    00:57:45 unidentified man performs a song in Pennsylvania German, accompanied by guitar and other voices
    00:59:37 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    01:00:01 unidentified man performs a song in Pennsylvania German, accompanied by guitar and other voices
    01:02:40 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    01:03:04 unidentified man, a guitar, and other voices perform "Go Down Moses" (sung in English)
    01:05:18 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    01:05:50 unidentified man performs "Battle Hymn of the Republic" (sung in English), accompanied by guitar and other voices
    01:08:06 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    01:08:16 unidentified man performs "Santa Claus Is Coming to Town" in English, accompanied by guitar and other voices, plus whistling for a verse
    01:10:02 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    01:10:28 unidentified man performs a song (sung in English), accompanied by guitar and other voices
    01:11:54 unidentified man speaks in Pennsylvania German
    01:12:16 unidentified man performs a song (in Pennsylvania German or German), accompanied by guitar and other voices; at one point, audience joins singing
    01:14:18 applause and various sounds
    01:16:02 orchestral Christmas music
    01:24:06 orchestral Christmas music
    01:24:41 unidentified man speaks in German or Pennsylvania German; another man speaks in English
    01:25:54 orchestral Christmas music (beginning with "Jingle Bells")
    01:28:50 general audience noises
    See the digitization note for SR021, Side A.
    00:00:21 Don Yoder speaks in Pennsylvania German.
    00:00:59 instrumental music (the end of the piece)
    00:01:52 Don Yoder speaks in Pennsylvania German and English (may be part of SR021, Side A)
  - Sound recording, 1961, RAA 46856; 1 sound tape reel (00:33:10): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR022)
    Recorded at the St. Anthony Festival, Glassboro, New Jersey.
    00:00:01 unidentified person asks interview subject to identify herself
    00:00:07 Ann Cannett Balboni (?) gives her name, address, and age; talks about making a vow to St. Anthony that if St. Anthony healed her son, she'd go barefoot for the rest of her life (her son was healed); also made a vow to have her husband healed; [not deciphered, at 00:01:01-00:01:05], got the idea from her own wish; had seen it before, she is the only one in Glassboro; opinion of how it has "paid off"
    00:02:00 Balboni's husband believes that what they're doing is because they were brought up to believe in miracles and thank St. Anthony for responding and giving them what they asked for; in his own experience, he has witnessed these things; if you want something you have to sacrifice yourself
    00:03:51 (singing can be heard in background) unidentified man gives history of St. Anthony Beneficial Society: founded in 1919, in Glassboro, New Jersey; purpose was primarily for mutual aid; main objective to give sick benefit, death, benefit, and to assist members who may be in financial distress; society was founded with about 102 members (another man interjects here, about 00:04:59); ups and downs in terms of members count; assessment of how many were members; organization has enjoyed success; about 260 members now; it has good reputation in town, county, and state; celebration of the Feast of St. Anthony, as close to June 13 as possible
    00:06:49 Anthony Miranda (second-generation member): joined organization to preserve and carry on traditions of organization; fraternal and social benefits
    00:07:47 Pasquale di Giovanni (organized the society?): purpose of society to help Italians in Glassboro to get to know each other, for mutual aid, including spiritual aid, etc.; society had its first event on Labor Day 1919; got charter on October 28, 1919; society not politically affiliated
    00:10:48 John Brigandi (past president of the society): affiliated with the celebration committee for 16 or 17 years; talks about the two-day festivities; Mass on Saturday; procession on Saturday afternoon; efforts involved in procession; includes two bands and three floats; other organization participate; a queen is chosen; involvement of children in procession; length of march; benediction at church after procession; after supper, band begins the band concert; fireworks end the celebration; sermon is always in Italian; one of the founders has for years made a crucifix of flowers for years, and carried it; his sons continue the tradition; carrying the St. Anthony's statue; people giving gifts for different vows; putting money on saint; size of statue of the saint
    00:15:44 Stephen [sp?] di Pasquale (new president or president-elect) of the society: believes that society's traditions will be continued
    00:16:22 Sam Todaro, third-generation member of the society: grandfather was a founder; society's growth over the years; enduring nature of the organization; role of youth in organization
    00:17:49 unidentified man emphasizes the pattern that the organization set consisted of elderly men as leaders, but that Steve's youth is great for the organization
    00:18:31 Pete Grillo [?] (past president of the organization): responsible for getting youth of organization to include sports in the organization; softball team was winner or runner-up for 10 years; organization still affiliated in sports; organization also has a bowling league, as well as a mixed league with the Ladies Auxiliary
    00:19:59 unidentified man: important to fraternal nature of the organization: after bowling, couples have coffee and doughnuts; cordial, friendly atmosphere promotes good will; social nights for benefit of members (although outsiders can also come to fulfill complement of the hall, with members getting priority entry); others not of same religious faith or national heritage also come; cohesiveness between members of organization and members of community
    00:21:27 unidentified man: fathers, uncles, and grandfathers in organization were anxious to get educational opportunities for their children; in membership, there are teachers, doctors, and other professional people
    00:22:28 unidentified man says he is practically typical example of second- or third-generation of membership getting an education
    00:22:56 John [no surname given]: member of Juvenile Conference Committee; purpose is to straighten kids out before they get to jail
    00:23:22 unidentified man: members are leaders in other organizations in the community
    00:23:44 several men have a conversation
    00:24:07 Jim Dealy gives some of his titles
    00:24:36 unidentified man: Steve di Pasquale has been president of St. Bridget's parochial school for two years
    00:25:04 unidentified man: society has pride in its membership
    00:25:20 unidentified man: trustee of St. Bridget's church
    00:25:31 unidentified man: organizational was originally nationalistic, but has since branched out
    00:25:59 unidentified man thanks Pasquale di Giovani and other founders
    00:26:17 unidentified man: jewelry given by members of the community, in making vows; particular examples; jewelry becomes property of St. Anthony Society and cannot be returned; every year, the jewelry is put on the statue
    00:27:31 unidentified man (with interjections by a woman): St. Anthony is protector [dominator?] of fire, some biographical details about St. Anthony, what St. Anthony wore and what it means; the interview subject's son wore garb for more than five years because he made a vow; boy not very talkative until a vow was made on his behalf (by his parents?)
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RAA 46857; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:32:11, Side B: 00:32:09): analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR023)
    Recorded at the "Symposium on Rural Hymnody," hosted by Berea College, April 27-29, 1979. Session C: A Demonstration of Lining Hymnody by members of the Mt. Olivet Regular Baptist Church, led by Elder Elwood Cornett; reel 1 of 2
    00:00:01 Bill Talmadge [?] introduces performances of lining hymnody; mentions I.D. (?)
    00:06:06 Elwood Cornett introduces church members: Sister Mary Dixon, Alice Little, Glen Hampton, Oliver Mullins, William Lusk, Jr., Mrs. Oliver Mullins, Karen Mullins, Mildred Lusk, Kathy Cornett; they are all from the Mt. Olivet Regular Baptist Church, Blackey, Kentucky
    00:13:21 church group performs "Brethren We Have Met Again"
    00:16:42 Elwood Cornett: spoken passage
    00:18:48 church group performs "Tarry With Me, O My Savior"
    00:22:55 Elwood Cornett: spoken passage
    00:25:55 church group performs "I'll Go Where You Want Me To Go"
    00:30:03 Elwood Cornett: spoken passage (cut off, continues on SR023, Side B)
    00:00:02 Elwood Cornett: spoken passage (continued from SR023, Side A)
    00:01:43 church group performs "Jesus Left His Home in Glory"
    00:04:55 Elwood Cornett introduces Charles Jones, who joined the group from the audience (see SR023, Side A)
    00:05:28 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform "Every Moment Brings Me Nearer"
    00:08:16 Elwood Cornett describes how a service would proceed
    00:11:14 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform a song (on page 32 of book referenced in the recording)
    00:15:17 Elwood Cornett introduces the next song
    00:16:22 church group, plus Charles Jones, perform a song